<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on Ean Jacob Gayban</title>
    <link>https://ejacobg.com/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on Ean Jacob Gayban</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 15:53:44 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ejacobg.com/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>.NET Microservices: Architecture for Containerized .NET Applications</title>
      <link>https://ejacobg.com/notes/dotnet-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 23:47:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ejacobg.com/notes/dotnet-microservices/</guid>
      <description>After all that talk last time about how I&amp;rsquo;m not gonna read textbooks anymore, here I am with another reading project. This book just happened to catch me when I was low on both ideas and time, so reading just made the most sense.
If Microservices in .NET was a little below my level, then this book was definitely a much better fit. I found it particularly relevant in my new job, especially since many of the patterns and practices discussed were present in the codebases I&amp;rsquo;m trying to learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pastebin Q&amp;A</title>
      <link>https://ejacobg.com/notes/pastebin-qna/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 14:47:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ejacobg.com/notes/pastebin-qna/</guid>
      <description>Below are several questions I&amp;rsquo;ve asked and answered while in the process of building the Pastebin project. I originally wrote them down to help keep track of what I was currently working on, but I found myself revisiting the same questions from time to time. I figure this may not be the last time I&amp;rsquo;ll need the answers to these questions, so I&amp;rsquo;m posting them here for future reference. I cannot guarantee the correctness of any answers presented herein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microservices in .NET</title>
      <link>https://ejacobg.com/notes/microservices-in-dotnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 11:19:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ejacobg.com/notes/microservices-in-dotnet/</guid>
      <description>ReviewA week after finishing the Hacker News Feed project, I had found another book to work through: Christian Horsdal&amp;rsquo;s Microservices in .NET, Second Edition (2021). I was (and still am) interested in learning more about both microservices and the .NET stack, so this book couldn&amp;rsquo;t have come at a better time. The difficulty seemed reasonable, it had some projects I could take a look at, and it even covered deploying to Azure, which I did manage to get working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Services</title>
      <link>https://ejacobg.com/notes/testing-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 22:19:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ejacobg.com/notes/testing-services/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say that some parts of your code want to make use of a key-value store that looks something like this:
package kv // Store stores positive integers. type Store interface { Get(key int) int // Returns -1 if the key is not present. Put(key, value int) // Inserts a new item, updating it if present. Delete(key int) // No-op if key is not present. } You might then have some concrete implementations for your store:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hands-On Software Engineering With Golang</title>
      <link>https://ejacobg.com/notes/hands-on-software-engineering-with-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2023 10:49:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ejacobg.com/notes/hands-on-software-engineering-with-golang/</guid>
      <description>Some notes and my overall experience reading through Achilleas Anagnostopoulos&amp;rsquo;s Hands-On Software Engineering with Golang (2020). This won&amp;rsquo;t cover everything discussed in the book, just the points I thought were most helpful.
ReviewI went into this book thinking I could hit a lot of the keywords on my list: Docker, Kubernetes, gRPC, concurrency, software engineering, testing, and a project to add to my portfolio. In the loosest sense you could say I &amp;ldquo;hit&amp;rdquo; all of these topics, but some were more focused on than others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
