<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Ean Jacob Gayban</title>
    <link>https://ejacobg.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Ean Jacob Gayban</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 15:53:56 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ejacobg.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Links &#39;R&#39; Us</title>
      <link>https://ejacobg.com/projects/links-r-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 16:15:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ejacobg.com/projects/links-r-us/</guid>
      <description>This project was made to accompany my reading of Hands-On Software Engineering with Golang. Please note that the vast majority of this code was not written by me, however I did make a couple of meaningful changes: (1) I reorganized all the packages into a form I liked better (similar to the Standard Package Layout), (2) I rewrote a few of the tests (add links) to use the standard testing package rather than GoCheck, and (3) I got rid of a lot of old/deprecated code since the project isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly up-to-date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tourney Tracker</title>
      <link>https://ejacobg.com/projects/tourney-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 23:14:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ejacobg.com/projects/tourney-tracker/</guid>
      <description>This project was made to practice/review some concepts discussed in Alex Edwards&amp;rsquo;s Let&amp;rsquo;s Go and Let&amp;rsquo;s Go Further books. I also wanted to get a feel for how I wanted to structure my (web) applications in the future. Below is some discussion on the various sources that helped influence how this project came to be structured.
Let&amp;rsquo;s Go/SnippetboxI repurposed a lot of the template-handling code from the Snippetbox project into the Tourney Tracker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker News Saved</title>
      <link>https://ejacobg.com/projects/hn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 18:37:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ejacobg.com/projects/hn/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a lot of time on Hacker News lately, and like many other people I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to building a large backlog of links to several blog posts, articles, and discussions. It feels like a waste for me to clutter my bookmarks with links I end up not reading, especially when many of these links are interesting, insightful, or happen to be relevant to whatever I&amp;rsquo;m working on at the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
